# **Denis Aleksandrov**

Adobe Commerce (Magento) Developer

denis.v.aleksandrov@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/denal05 0038977975812 Skopje, Karpoš, 1000, North Macedonia

20+ years of IT experience. Medior Magento developer. A well-organized software engineer. Developed Magento 2 e-commerce shops, LAMP-stack web apps, iOS mobile apps, Java enterprise apps, and embedded systems firmware. Had a role in two FDA-certified medical devices.

# **Work Experience**

#### **MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER**

Nov 2023 - Aug 2024

SYNCIT GROUP | remote

Delivered Magento upgrades, created Docker environments, and removed malware.

- Upgraded Magento websites of existing production environments from 2.3 and 2.4 to 2.6 and 2.7
- Created various Docker environments for Magento 2
- · Detected and removed malware
- Customized the classic Magento 2 multi-page checkout

#### **MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER**

NTT DATA SPAIN | remote

Backend Magento 2 developer coding modules according to user stories and providing defect fixes in staging and production environments.

- · Worked extensively on the "bulk order status update" functionality
- · Integrated Algolia search
- Customized the "onepage" checkout

#### **MAGENTO 2 TECH SUPPORT ENGINEER**

Jun 2021 - Dec 2022

ON TAP GROUP | remote

Provided first-tier technical support to e-commerce clients via the help desk and live chat, covering products and services, triaging issues, and providing partial or full solutions.

- The products included extensions for Magento 2, OpenCart, PrestaShop, and WooCommerce
- The services included custom B2B and B2C Magento 2 module development and bi-weekly deployment of modules from scratch, custom modification of 3rd-party modules, and integration of 3rd-party modules
- The software development process used an agile software development methodology with bi-weekly sprints

#### PROJECT LEAD & MAGENTO 2 DEVELOPER

Dec 2018 - Apr 2021

CODEWELL UNLIMITED DOO | N. Macedonia

Responsible for project management using Scrumban methodology. Mostly backend and some frontend development for the e-commerce platform Magento 2, running on Amazon Web Services. For more information regarding the projects I worked on, please see https://denal05.github.io

- Full-stack development on Magento 2
- Extensively used AWS EC2
- Developed the Magento 2 piece of a book publishing company's ecosystem for selling, buying, reading, and reviewing printed books and eBooks, with an eBook reader app for Android and iOS
- Developed the Magento 2 piece of a children's merchandise store integrated with a custom event organizer web app

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

INFORM DOO | N. Macedonia

Mar 2011 - Oct 2018 PROJECT MANAGER

Responsible mostly for project management. Other responsibilities included regulatory compliance, quality assurance, technical writing, software development, system administration, operations, procurement, human resources and corporate social responsibility. Major clients between 2011 and 2018 were IntriCon, Gauge Telematics and SnapBar.

# JUNIOR DEVELOPER | JUNIOR TESTER | CONFIGURATION MANAGER

Feb 2009 - Mar 2011

QINSHIFT (formerly Seavus) | N. Macedonia

Studied the ARM architecture. Utilised working procedures and protocols fundamental to source code development within Seavus. Performed testing on software as part of Quality Assurance. Responsible for Configuration Management of software as part of Quality Assurance.

## **COMPUTER SCIENCE TEACHER**

Sep 2007 - Apr 2008

MOREAU CATHOLIC HIGH SCHOOL | Hayward, California, USA

Instructed students on three subjects: Advanced Placement Computer Science for the College Board AP CS A exam, Introduction to Computer Science using Java, and Computer Essentials with Microsoft Office. Clarified fundamental Computer Science concepts. Encouraged discipline, diligence, and design.

#### APPLICATION ENGINEER

May 2007 - Oct 2007

MOVELL SOFTWARE, INC. | Hayward, California, USA

Integrated weekly source code releases of Movell's real-time remote diagnostic software engine I-DEAL onto a development board running embedded Linux using the GNU ARM toolchain. Demonstrated the diagnostic software to potential customers.

### **ENTRY-LEVEL JAVA DEVELOPER**

Jan 2007 - Apr 2007

DIVVIO | Hayward, California, USA

Coordinated release builds, extended functionality of media player integration, and implemented new features of the flagship product: a Web2.0 application that aggregates video and audio content on the Internet.

Apr 2005 - Dec 2005 IT SPECIALIST

NORMAN CHRYSLER JEEP DODGE | Norman, Oklahoma, USA

Single-handedly maintained and expanded the entire IT infrastructure (including desktops, servers, databases, and networking equipment) of a major automobile dealership with satellite offices. Made decisions in purchasing and coordinating with technology goods and services. Involved with all aspects of security.

## MICROCOMPUTER LAB TECHNICIAN (HELP DESK)

Apr 2000 - Oct 2003

Office of IT at the University of Central Oklahoma | Edmond, Oklahoma, USA

Assisted Technology Support with work orders, including PC rebuilds/installation/removal/upgrades, and basic and intermediate troubleshooting. Helped with the disposition of surplus computer equipment, including destroying data, salvaging parts, and rebuilding PCs. Checked IT computer labs and delivered printer supplies as needed.

# **Projects**

### Extra Blog module for Magento 2

Oct 2023 - Oct 2023

An extra Magento 2 module, with plugins for the "Blog" module, built as an exercise for the M.academy "Magento 2 Coding Kickstart" course by Mark Shust.

# Blog module for Magento 2

A Magento 2 module built as an exercise for the M.academy "Magento 2 Coding Kickstart" course by Mark Shust with additional functionality.

# docker-compose-plain-vanilla-magento-2.4

Nov 2023 - Aug 2024

Configuration files for a Docker container running plain-vanilla Magento Open Source 2.4

# **Volunteer Experience**

# Localization Volunteer (Macedonian language)

Jul 2011 - Present

YouVersion

Faithfully serving as a volunteer on the team that localizes the most popular Bible app for iOS, Android, and web into the Macedonian language.

Financial Officer Jul 2013 - Oct 2017

SEAM (IFES/InterVarsity in N. Macedonia)

Responsible for finances, from paying bills and taxes to planning annual budgets, fundraising, grant proposals, and coordinating with the certified public accountant and financial officers of the umbrella organization International Fellowship of Evangelical Students (IFES/InterVarsity).

Team Member Oct 2010 - Jun 2013

HBM (CBMC in N. Macedonia)

Participated in a Christian Business Network in North Macedonia - a marketplace ministry.

## References

# Gerald Pesjak, Tech Lead at Technology Everywhere

I appreciated your good vibes and good quality of code working with you as a developer in an ecommerce solution for Orange Belgium. You have an excellent team spirit and were always open to give others a helping hand if needed. Your understanding of magento2 is very good and your quality of code is well considering the PSR standards. I recommend working with Denis in a magento2 project as a developer.

# Bryan Brenchley, Mentor for New Business & Tech Startups

Denis worked for me at INform for over 7 1/2 years. He was always ready to work above and beyond. He worked in many capacities - QA, Project Management, Customer Service, and Software Development. His attention to detail was helpful in all job capacities. Our clients spoke highly of his organizational and communication skills. He is a team player with a positive attitude. I gladly recommend Denis to be a part of helping you find the IT solutions you are looking for!

# **Core Skills**

Magento 2, Malware detection and removal, Docker, PHP, SQL, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, KnockoutJS, Linux, LAMP, Git, Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, Postman, payment gateways, PhpStorm, Bitbucket, Confluence, Jira, Node.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQLite, Firebase, Amazon Web Services (AWS), REST APIs, Swift, SwiftUI, Objective-C, Core ML, Realm Database, Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE), Core Data, Core Location, Core Bluetooth, Create ML, Xcode, Java, C, C++, Perl, TypeScript, Express.js, embedded systems, ARM, IAR Embedded Workbench, Arduino, Qt, ECommerce Platform, Google Analytics, Lifecycle Development, Ability To Work In A Team

# **Education**

San Francisco Bay University (formerly Northwestern Polytechnic University)

May 2006 - Apr 2008

Master of Science Electrical Engineering

**University of Central Oklahoma** 

Dec 1999 - Apr 2005

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

Languages

English (fluent), Serbian (intermediate), Croatian (intermediate), Bulgarian (Intermediate)

**Certificates** 

Transform Magento 2 Admin Grids & Forms

Oct 2023

M.academy

**Magento 2 Coding Kickstart** 

Sep 2023

M.academy

iOS & Swift - The Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp

Jan 2021

Udemy

**Swift 4 Fundamentals** 

Oct 2018

Sololearn

iOS Advanced Training in Objective-C

Jul 2016

Seavus Education and Development Center

iOS Basic Training in Objective-C

Jun 2016

Seavus Education and Development Center

Sun Microsystems Certified Java Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 - 06/05/2006

Jun 2006

Sun Microsystems

## **Interests**

hiking, Baroque music, Jazz, Blues, Ethno music, Tango Nuevo, Progressive Rock, Electronic music, Gospel music, Worship